<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</title>
    <link>//bulimov.me/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//bulimov.me/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Pelican to Hugo for this blog</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2021/02/16/pelical-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2021/02/16/pelical-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Since I no longer enjoy working with Python in any shape or form, it was only a matter of time (mostly a matter of my free time) for this to happen. I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated this blog from Pelican static site generator (written in Python) to Hugo (written in Go).&#xA;It by no means reflects on Pelican as a piece of software (it&amp;rsquo;s actually pretty good). It&amp;rsquo;s more about my disdain for Python, and awesome experience I had with Hugo and Go language in general.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My new Scale Models gallery</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/personal/models-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/personal/models-gallery/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just published my new site - personal Scale Models Gallery.&#xA;Model making is my main and favorite hobby, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to build a whole new site just to write about it.&#xA;I just love doing something without the computer, it&amp;rsquo;s an awesome way to de-stress and detox.&#xA;Also I love to make notes about things I do, read, watch or play. And one day I&amp;rsquo;ve just realized that I want to turn my notes about making scale models with all this wip photos and comments about quality or tools into something bigger.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
