<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Watch on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</title>
    <link>//bulimov.me/tags/watch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Watch on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//bulimov.me/tags/watch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing a custom Garmin Instinct 2 watch face</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2025/01/12/custom-garmin-watchface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2025/01/12/custom-garmin-watchface/</guid>
      <description>The search for my perfect retro watch face I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying my Garmin Instinct 2 a great deal, but after getting a Casio Royale I yearned to make my Garmin more &amp;lsquo;retro&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;I found a great existing watch face called &amp;ldquo;7 Segments Simple&amp;rdquo; which imitates the look of classic 7-segment displays.&#xA;It was almost perfect for me, except that I wanted to see the current weather right on the watch face.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making a wooden Watch Box with hand tools only</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2025/01/11/making-watch-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2025/01/11/making-watch-box/</guid>
      <description>I have a very modest watch collection, and my wife also has a couple of watches. Over the last few years, I returned to wearing non-smartwatches more and more.&#xA;Naturally, I was not happy with my watches lying in the cupboard where we forget about their existence and hence seldom wear them.&#xA;In an attempt to solve this, I went ahead and bought the most basic watch box from Amazon for 15GBP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modding my Casio Royale (AE1200) Watch</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2024/10/26/modding-casio-royale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2024/10/26/modding-casio-royale/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I mentioned that I prefer to wear &amp;lsquo;dumb&amp;rsquo; watches over the weekend, mainly for reasons related to mental health and hygiene.&#xA;At that moment, my one and only weekend watch remained a wonderful mechanical piece from Hamilton, Khaki Officer Mechanical, with truly old-school ETA6497 movement originating from pocket watches. I had it for over ten years for sure, wore it exclusively for over half of those years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching to a dumber smartwatch</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2024/10/04/dumber-smartwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2024/10/04/dumber-smartwatch/</guid>
      <description>It all started when I read a piece from The Verge about a new Casio watch back in July. It described a simple digital watch that only shows time, counts steps and has Bluetooth to export steps data to the phone.&#xA;Now that really caught my attention because I myself was struggling with my Apple Watch for many months (years?) now. The way it negatively affected my mental health and anxiety was clear to me for quite some time, but yet I was not ready to part with the benefits of using it, mainly related to fitness.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
