<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</title>
    <link>//bulimov.me/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//bulimov.me/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fun experiments with Go memory usage</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2024/01/27/golang-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2024/01/27/golang-memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While working on a big Go program that processes data I began to wonder if our memory usage is adequate for the amount of data we deal with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My starting point was this question - &lt;em&gt;If the output of this service is a text file that is only few Gigabytes in size,&#xA;why does it take significantly more memory to produce this file?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This lead to a series of experiments which I hope will be interesting for anyone caring about writing efficient code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python 3.6 f-strings rant</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/it/python3-fstrings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/it/python3-fstrings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python 3.6 introduced a new way to format strings, called&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/3.6/reference/lexical_analysis.html#f-strings&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formatted string literals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;or just &lt;em&gt;f-strings&lt;/em&gt;. Everyone on the internet&#xA;seem to be happy about it. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For starters, Python 3 already had 3 built-in ways of doing it before.&#xA;Just think about it&amp;hellip; 3 ways to &lt;em&gt;format strings&lt;/em&gt; in language that declares simplicity as a goal:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There should be one&amp;ndash; and preferably only one &amp;ndash;obvious way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I became a programmer</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/personal/how-i-became-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/personal/how-i-became-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After reading a lot of blog posts about becoming a programmer recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to write my own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It will be a bit different because of two factors:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a Software Engineer, but a Production Engineer/SRE/Admin;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m from Russia, where CS education is vastly different.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;school-years&#34;&gt;School years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;School in Russia is 10 or 11 years and you start at the age of ~7  and end it at ~17&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As far as I recall, my first programming experience was with&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logo_(programming_language)&#34;&gt;LogoWriter&lt;/a&gt; in elementary school.&#xA;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad at it, and even enjoyed it a lot, but our LogoWriter course ended quite fast,&#xA;and since then I can&amp;rsquo;t remember anything useful related to programming in my school courses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes about type systems in popular languages</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/it/more-typing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/it/more-typing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been kind of out of my comfort zone last 3 weeks,&#xA;and was trying to use as many new languages and technologies as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used C++, JavaScript, React, PHP and &lt;a href=&#34;http://hacklang.org&#34;&gt;Hack&lt;/a&gt; to name a few,&#xA;and I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed really cool thing - many popular programming&#xA;languages are moving towards mixing best of static and dynamic typing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;C++ (statically typed language) now has &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt; keyword, specifying that compiler&#xA;should deduce type of variable or return type of function automatically;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;JavaScript has &lt;a href=&#34;https://flowtype.org&#34;&gt;Flow&lt;/a&gt; - static type checker from Facebook,&#xA;and there is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.typescriptlang.org&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt; from Microsoft which compiles to JS;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;PHP has type hints since version 5, and they are greatly improved in PHP7;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hacklang.org&#34;&gt;Hack&lt;/a&gt; has even more advanced type annotations than PHP;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Python added type hints in 3.5, which recently &lt;a href=&#34;//bulimov.me/it/python-typing&#34;&gt;made me very excited&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And it looks like all big companies are using this stuff extensively!&#xA;Isn&amp;rsquo;t it awesome? After mainly using &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; for last year,&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m super excited seeing how dynamically typed languages become safer&#xA;with type hints, and how C++ brings convenience and ease of dynamic typing to its users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Type Hints are awesome</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/it/python-typing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/it/python-typing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really love &lt;a href=&#34;http://jvns.ca&#34;&gt;Julia Evans&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;, she writes with such excitement&#xA;and enthusiasm about every new bit of technology she learns. For me, this is what&#xA;makes our job so great - we can learn something new and cool almost every day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And recently I&amp;rsquo;ve felt very excited with some of new abilities Python&#xA;now have. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about including of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0484/&#34;&gt;PEP 484&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;which describes Type Hints, in Python 3.5 (old news, I know).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
