<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Video Games on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</title>
    <link>//bulimov.me/tags/video-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video Games on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//bulimov.me/tags/video-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Year With Xbox</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2022/10/03/year-with-xbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2022/10/03/year-with-xbox/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago I made a decision not to continue with PlayStation as my main console, and switch to Xbox Series instead. It was a risk, as I have been a reasonably happy PS customer through PS3 and PS4 eras.&#xA;Now, after a year with Xbox Series S I can sum up my experience and compare notes.&#xA;tldr; It is great and I’m very happy with this decision.&#xA;I can safely say that all the hopes I put into switching to Xbox have realized!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I’m picking Xbox for new generation</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2021/08/07/why-xbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2021/08/07/why-xbox/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: this is not an objective comparison, it&amp;rsquo;s my personal, extremely subjective choice.&#xA;Here is why I’m not buying PS5, despite having PS3 since 2010 and PS4 since 2014.&#xA;And no, it’s not because it too hard to get now :-)&#xA;The main reason is simple: For me, PS5 brings no excitement. Now let me explain why.&#xA;PS3 to PS4 transition was already kinda boring. I was quite ok with graphics level PS3 provided, and the main improvement that PS4 borough for me was normal digital store (where you don’t have to download patches after you just downloaded full game), and a slightly better controller (albeit with worse battery life).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
