<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</title>
    <link>//bulimov.me/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//bulimov.me/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Added Dark Mode support</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2025/05/11/blog-dark-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2025/05/11/blog-dark-mode/</guid>
      <description>Now this blog supports Dark Mode, if the browser has it set as preferred.&#xA;I myself switched to using Dark Mode on some of my devices, but only recently noticed that my very own blog didn&amp;rsquo;t have the support for it.&#xA;Thankfully adding it was super easy, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to go much further than this blog&amp;rsquo;s theme Issues on Github.&#xA;The author of this lovely xmin theme provided an answer in the issue #67:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 years of blogging</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2024/07/31/11-years-of-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2024/07/31/11-years-of-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Wow, time flies. Just realized that this blog turned 11 this summer.&#xA;wc -w tells me that I wrote almost 40k words in 81 posts over those years, not bad at all.&#xA;I managed to post at least once every year since 2013 except for 2019 and 2020 when I was too busy with work.&#xA;For me, writing is a very good exercise. It helps to better shape and express my thoughts, and writing technical things often highlights areas I don’t fully understand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moved to a new domain</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2022/09/25/moved-to-new-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2022/09/25/moved-to-new-domain/</guid>
      <description>This site just moved to a new domain bulimov.me. Long overdue move of course, I bought the new domain years ago&amp;hellip;&#xA;Anyway, the only interesting bit about this is how I&amp;rsquo;m trying to keep the old links alive with a little bit of HTML magic.&#xA;Using a very basic python script I&amp;rsquo;ve created a dedicated Github repo with a directory structure mirroring this site, where each index.html consists of something like this:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code-like linting for prose</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2022/01/16/prose-lint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2022/01/16/prose-lint/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of static analysis and linting for code.&#xA;If a computer can do it automatically - why rely on humans to do the same thing?&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons why I&amp;rsquo;m such a big proponent of static typing.&#xA;I try to bring linting everywhere:&#xA;When I had to deal with huge and complex HAProxy configs - I wrote a linter myself. When later at different place I had to deal with complicated business logic expressed as a state machine - I used Python AST to write a linter for it, and analyze cycles, dead ends and complexity.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
