<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Alexander Bulimov - production engineer's notes. - Personal</title><link href="http://bulimov.ru/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://bulimov.ru/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://bulimov.ru/</id><updated>2018-02-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated><entry><title>My new Scale Models gallery</title><link href="http://bulimov.ru/personal/models-gallery/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-01T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-02-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Bulimov</name></author><id>tag:bulimov.ru,2018-02-01:/personal/models-gallery/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just published my new site - personal &lt;a href="//models.bulimov.ru"&gt;Scale Models Gallery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model_building"&gt;Model making&lt;/a&gt; is my main and favorite hobby, so I've decided to build a whole new site just to write about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just love doing something without the computer, it's an awesome way to de-stress and detox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I love to make notes about things I do, read, watch or play. And one day I've just realized that I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just published my new site - personal &lt;a href="//models.bulimov.ru"&gt;Scale Models Gallery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model_building"&gt;Model making&lt;/a&gt; is my main and favorite hobby, so I've decided to build a whole new site just to write about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just love doing something without the computer, it's an awesome way to de-stress and detox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I love to make notes about things I do, read, watch or play. And one day I've just realized that I want to turn
my notes about making scale models with all this &lt;em&gt;wip&lt;/em&gt; photos and comments about quality or tools into something bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've already had great experience with static site generators, so it was just a matter of choosing one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For reason of being fed up with python at work, and also because I love Go language, I chose &lt;a href="http://gohugo.io"&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's much easier to set up, it's much faster than &lt;a href="http://getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; I'm still using for this blog,
and it seems to be more flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I chose the generator and a &lt;a href="https://github.com/eueung/hugo-casper-two"&gt;theme&lt;/a&gt;, which is a port of
&lt;em&gt;Casper&lt;/em&gt; theme from &lt;strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/strong&gt; blogging platform, I just had to convert my Evernote notes into a proper site, which I did in a couple of evenings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm pretty happy with the result so far, &lt;a href="//models.bulimov.ru"&gt;models.bulimov.ru&lt;/a&gt; looks nice both on desktop and mobile, and does basically
everything I wanted from it, which is just picture-heavy posts and aggregation by tags per scale and make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have to add Google Analytics and Discuss to it, but even now my ego is pretty much satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Golang"></category><category term="Hugo"></category></entry><entry><title>Benefits of upgradable laptops</title><link href="http://bulimov.ru/personal/laptop-upgrade/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-31T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-01-31T00:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Bulimov</name></author><id>tag:bulimov.ru,2018-01-31:/personal/laptop-upgrade/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been concerned by a low amount of memory in my &lt;strong&gt;Asus UX310U&lt;/strong&gt; laptop for quite a long time,
but as I used it quite lightly at home, it never became a problem. It has perfectly capable Intel i3-6100U CPU,
nice FullHD screen, 5h+ of battery life, so it made no sense to change the laptop just because of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously 4Gb of RAM is kind of low by modern …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been concerned by a low amount of memory in my &lt;strong&gt;Asus UX310U&lt;/strong&gt; laptop for quite a long time,
but as I used it quite lightly at home, it never became a problem. It has perfectly capable Intel i3-6100U CPU,
nice FullHD screen, 5h+ of battery life, so it made no sense to change the laptop just because of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously 4Gb of RAM is kind of low by modern standards, but when I bought it I wasn't planning to use anything resource-heavy like IDE at home, just terminal and browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only case when the lack of RAM was obvious is when the laptop was used by two users. As I share it with my wife,
it was often the case, and switching users was quite painful, but I didn't use it often enough for it to piss me off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I've started to use it more often, for instance to work on latest &lt;a href="http://adventofcode.com"&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt;
coding challenge, and it quickly became a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily for me Asus was generous enough to allow RAM upgrades in UX310U, so I could add up to 8Gb to existing 4Gb that are soldered on the motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I bought another 4Gb module, unscrewed the lid and to my surprise not only there was a slot for SODIMM RAM, but also a place for SATA 2.5inch drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I had one spare 128Gb SATA SSD in my stash, just after 10 minutes I ended up with double RAM and double the storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately now the trend is to just solder everything on the logic board, and don't leave any means for upgrade. 
Given that I've just greatly benefited from ability to upgrade RAM it's very sad to think that
with my next laptop I'll most likely be left without any way to improve it except for buying a new one (like current MacBook users already have to)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Experience"></category></entry><entry><title>What I read on the internet (2017 edition)</title><link href="http://bulimov.ru/personal/what-i-read-2017/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-01T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Bulimov</name></author><id>tag:bulimov.ru,2017-06-01:/personal/what-i-read-2017/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;About a year ago I was asked in comments what do I read on the internet.
Back then, the list consisted from blogs of open-source products I've been using (like Atom, Elasticsearch, Icinga, Grafana), some personal blogs (Lennart Poettering, Aphyr, Julia Evans), some company blogs (Github Engineering) and basic tech press (Ars Techica, The Verge, Phoronix, LWN). And two mail lists - Devops Weekly and Golang Weekly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I've been asked …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;About a year ago I was asked in comments what do I read on the internet.
Back then, the list consisted from blogs of open-source products I've been using (like Atom, Elasticsearch, Icinga, Grafana), some personal blogs (Lennart Poettering, Aphyr, Julia Evans), some company blogs (Github Engineering) and basic tech press (Ars Techica, The Verge, Phoronix, LWN). And two mail lists - Devops Weekly and Golang Weekly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I've been asked if something have changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it did - I've almost stopped reading blogs of products I've been using,
because since I'm working in a Big IT Company™ now we tend to use in-house solutions, which means I don't care that much about Icinga, Grafana and so on. I still try to keep up with their progress, but maybe once per month or two. The only blog that I'm keeping eye on is &lt;a href="http://blog.atom.io/"&gt;Atom blog&lt;/a&gt; since I'm using Atom both at home and at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also list of personal blogs I'm reading grown up significantly,
now it's huge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="antirez.com"&gt;Antirez&lt;/a&gt; - blog by &lt;a href="redis.io"&gt;Redis&lt;/a&gt; author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="aphyr.com"&gt;Aphyr&lt;/a&gt; - long in-depth posts about distributed software testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/"&gt;Chris's Wiki&lt;/a&gt; - nice blog by Chris Siebenmann about various tech/admin stuff, updated very frequently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/"&gt;Coding Horror&lt;/a&gt; - mostly tech rants by Jeff Atwood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://danluu.com"&gt;Dan Luu&lt;/a&gt; - mostly philosophical thought on IT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://dave.cheney.net"&gt;Dave Cheney&lt;/a&gt; - mostly about &lt;a href="golang.org"&gt;Go language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://deliberate-software.com/"&gt;Deliberate software&lt;/a&gt; - witty blog about programming. &lt;a href="http://deliberate-software.com/haskell-is-the-dark-souls-of-programming/"&gt;Haskell is the Dark Souls of Programming&lt;/a&gt; is a must-read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://duartes.org/gustavo/blog/"&gt;Gustavo Duarte&lt;/a&gt; - some in-depth programming articles, not updated anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://henrikwarne.com/"&gt;Henrik Warne&lt;/a&gt; - mostly thoughts about being a programmer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://jvns.ca/"&gt;Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt; - one of my favorite blogs, always positive, always discovering something new.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://idea.popcount.org/"&gt;Marek's idea of the day&lt;/a&gt; - some crazy low-level stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/"&gt;Matthew Garrett&lt;/a&gt; - IoT and security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://0pointer.de/blog"&gt;Pid Eins&lt;/a&gt; - Lennart Poettering's blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://brennan.io/blog/"&gt;Stephen Brennan&lt;/a&gt; - random programming stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://steve-yegge.blogspot.com"&gt;Steve Yegge&lt;/a&gt; - mostly tech rants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/"&gt;Terence Eden&lt;/a&gt; - IoT and various tech stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rachelbythebay.com/w/"&gt;Rachel by the bay&lt;/a&gt; - Another top quality in-depth tech blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.not-a-kernel-guy.com/"&gt;Not a kernel guy&lt;/a&gt; - Alex Pakhunov'blog (in Russian) about Space X (he works there) and tech-related stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still on &lt;em&gt;Devops Weekly&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Golang Weekly&lt;/em&gt; mailing lists,
but tend to read they emails in batches once per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still read Ars Technica, The Verge, Phoronix and LWN.
List of company blogs grown up a bit and now consist of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://tech.dropbox.com"&gt;Dropbox tech blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://code.facebook.com/"&gt;Facebook Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://githubengineering.com/"&gt;Github Engineering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm using &lt;a href="https://feedly.com/"&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="getpocket.com"&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; to keep up with this amount of information.
I'm saving all interesting posts and articles to Pocket and then
try to read them when I have some free time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost forgot to mention &lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/linux"&gt;/r/linux on reddit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.
I try to read both couple of times per week.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogs"></category></entry><entry><title>How I became a programmer</title><link href="http://bulimov.ru/personal/how-i-became-a-programmer/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-30T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2016-09-30T00:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Bulimov</name></author><id>tag:bulimov.ru,2016-09-30:/personal/how-i-became-a-programmer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After reading a lot of blog posts about becoming a programmer recently, I've decided to write my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be a bit different because of two factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not a Software Engineer, but a Production Engineer/SRE/Admin;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm from Russia, where CS education is vastly different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;School years&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;School in Russia is 10 or 11 years and you start at the age of ~7  and end it at …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After reading a lot of blog posts about becoming a programmer recently, I've decided to write my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be a bit different because of two factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not a Software Engineer, but a Production Engineer/SRE/Admin;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm from Russia, where CS education is vastly different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;School years&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;School in Russia is 10 or 11 years and you start at the age of ~7  and end it at ~17&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I recall, my first programming experience was with
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logo_(programming_language)"&gt;LogoWriter&lt;/a&gt; in elementary school.
I wasn't bad at it, and even enjoyed it a lot, but our LogoWriter course ended quite fast,
and since then I can't remember anything useful related to programming in my school courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may imagine, personal computer was not a common thing in 90th in Russia,
so in my family it appeared only in 2000. The fun thing I remember about using Windows 98 first time
was me calling my mom and asking if I will be able to open a program again after I close it.
For me, 'closing' was like shutting down some factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, approximately during 9th year of school some boys in our class were attending some
external paid programming courses, where they were using
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delphi_(programming_language)"&gt;Borland Delphi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously they've shown other students some of their's programs, so I've tried to write something in Delphi on my own.
No surprise, I haven't written anything and became absolutely sure that programming is not my cup of tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So during school I developed only strong feeling that programming was to hard for me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;University&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During school years I was quite good at math, and not very good at physics,
so I decided to attend Applied Math Faculty of Moscow State Technical University of Civil Aviation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very soon I've discovered that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a LOT of physics in Applied Math program;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't like all this Calculus courses at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in Russian university you can't select or change courses once you've chosen your Faculty.
So every Faculty has pre-defined selection of various courses, all of which you must attend
and complete. At most you can change your Faculty, but it's a very difficult and painful process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system is quite stupid, as you have to learn all the stuff you don't like at all,
and all the stuff that you don't need at all. For instance, I have to attend and complete
some strange courses related to Civil Aviation, like 'History of Civil Aviation' and 'Economy of Civil Aviation',
some useless crap about Sociology, and many other useless courses. And everybody knew that this courses was useless,
nobody enjoyed them, but all of us had to complete them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what's worse -  you can't attend courses in your university that you are really interested in
if they are not in your Faculty program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, on our first year we had a lot of basic Borland Pascal programming classes, and I really enjoyed it.
By the end of the semester I was making money doing homework for other students
(as you can't really skip any courses in Russian university, you have to complete them somehow,
so it's a very common thing to pay for homework).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During all the University years I was making money doing various programming tasks and studies for other students,
so I sort of hacked the system and was able to 'attend' in some way other Faculty's courses. I even remember
writing an 'engine' in C++ to draw various 3D figures using DOS VESA driver for other Faculties, because I've got so
many orders from them that writing proper engine able to draw figures described as polygons in a simple text file
was easier than writing every project individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First two years we were learning some basic procedure-oriented programming in Pascal, and it wasn't that bad,
as it was my intro to programming and I learned a lot. I even recall implementing some simple algorithms,
like bubble sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, on third year we had a course called "Operating System basics" or something like that.
It was taught by &lt;a href="http://www.stolyarov.info"&gt;Andrey V. Stolyarov&lt;/a&gt;, very bizarre person, fanatic of Open Source
and C programming language. Despite all his oddness this course (which described Unix operating systems
and Linux kernel) was extremely good, and I had some really hard (but fun) time wrapping my head around C, pointers,
references, memory management and sockets. The course basically made us write chat client and server step-by-step,
and I was one of the few who actually accomplished this goal. It was very useful, I learned A LOT about operating
systems and low level stuff, and used Linux first time. And &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_C_Programming_Language"&gt;K&amp;amp;R The C Programming Language&lt;/a&gt; is still one of the best IT books I've ever read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next semester the course continued with C++,
and we've been implementing lots of data structures from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Template_Library"&gt;STL&lt;/a&gt;.
As I continued making money on other student's homework, I've implemented all basic data structures,
including linked lists, vectors and binary trees. It was extremely helpful and insightful, I learned about all
common data structures and algorithm complexity. And I learned about Object Oriented Programming and C++ templates.
It was all new to me, and of course I became a fan of OOP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, on fourth or fifth year, we had something about Relational Databases, and used &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LAMP_(software_bundle)"&gt;LAMP&lt;/a&gt; to build some basic &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt; interface.
I've learned about &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Database_normalization"&gt;normalization&lt;/a&gt;, JS and CSS, but the most
important thing was that I've finally realized that I wasn't the best in programming in the class - two students were
better programmers than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So university gave me A LOT. It basically introduced me to programming, gave a stong basic knowledge,
and even gave me a quite good overview of Unix-like OSes. But it also made me think I'm not good enough
for Software Engineer job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realizing that I wasn't the best programmer in the class somehow made me think that Software Engineer
career is not for me, so during my fifth year I attended a job which we call in Russia 'AnyKey'.
Basically it's the first level of IT helpdesk, but in my case it was a small company, so I was doing everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work PC was some old notebook with Windows XP, and it took 11 minutes to simply boot OS. I was very tired of it,
and ended up using Ubuntu 10.04. It worked really well, so I started to learn Linux and master bash and console tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My job included maintaining some basic &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proxy_server"&gt;Proxy Server&lt;/a&gt; on Windows XP.
Obviously this thing was illegal and unstable, so I've assembled another PC from spare parts and set up OpenSuSE 10
on it, because it has very nice graphical configuration utility for almost everything - YAST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led to using more Linux-based tools and servers, and I ended up re-implementing some really big and complex Excel
spreadsheet as a LAMP-based service. The code was absolutely terrible, as I didn't know about &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model–view–controller"&gt;MVC&lt;/a&gt;,
so it was a mess of HTML and PHP with tiny bits of JS for AJAX. But it was my first experience of programming
in a new domain and trying to implement something that other person vaguely wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So my first job gave me some real-world experience, a lot of Linux-related experience. I've learned bash
and started to use Vim.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Second job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I mastered bash, used some PHP, and after a year my company was bought by bigger company, so I've moved to bigger IT
department. At this point I was fluent with bash and terminal, but wasn't programming anything real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my new company I was dealing with some IP phones, and decided to implement shared phone directory for all
phone models we have had. This time I new about MVC, so used &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yii"&gt;Yii&lt;/a&gt;, and
the code was not that bad. I accomplished the goal of having universal phone directory with nice web-ui,
but have not open-sourced it as I just hadn't time to make proper installer. During this project I learned how
to use MVC properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around same time I decided to use &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chef_(software)"&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt; for all configuration
management, so I learned a bit of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ruby_(programming_language)"&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;
and started using &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercurial"&gt;Mercurial&lt;/a&gt; for revision control.
It was very cool to finally discover modern dynamic languages, which were very different from my PHP experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So my second job gave me even more Linux-related experience, I've built normal app using MVC pattern,
and I've finally tried modern dynamic language.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Third job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually I became bored being just a SysAdmin, and moved to a startup where I could be
something more - they called it 'DevOps engineer'. In this company I've switched from Chef to
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ansible_(software)"&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, and learned
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_(programming_language)"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; to fix a bug in a module I was using.
It was my first contribution to Open Source project, which I was very proud of.
I've been missing some modules in Ansible, so I just wrote them and contributed to upstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've fallen in love with Python and continued to use it for various monitoring scripts.
At the same time I've started to use unit tests, as my company was a Ruby shop, and all Software Engineers
relied on unit and functional test heavily. I was impressed how helpful it was, and became a huge fan
of automated testing and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_integration"&gt;CI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year later I've learned about &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haskell_(programming_language)"&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt;,
and as person with Applied Math background I was extremely interested. I've bought
&lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com"&gt;'Learn You A Haskell For Great Good'&lt;/a&gt;, read it,
and even written some basic games like Tic-Tac-Toe with AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It introduced me to functional programming, but I wasn't be able to write anything big and useful in Haskell.
But it gave me the understanding of how much a good typing system with good compiler can give a programmer
in terms of reliability and catching most of bugs &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; executing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So my job at startup gave me a lot of programming experience, I've started to use Python, auto-testing and CI,
learned about functional programming, and fell in love with modern static typing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fourth job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the startup I was working at became a bankrupt, I had to find another job.
It was surprisingly easy, and I became a Production Engineer in online cinema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this company I had a lot of great non-standard tasks, so I've been using my programming skills a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I was using Python for everything, as it was my language of choice, but I was interested in trying
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(programming_language)"&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; with it's great concurrency support
and static typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, one of my monitoring tasks required a good amount of concurrency, so I just wrote it in Go.
It was surprisingly easy, static typing was very helpful, and the tooling around language was very good.
Since then, I've continued to use Go more and more, and wrote some relatively big programs in it - like
my &lt;a href="https://github.com/abulimov/haproxy-lint"&gt;linter for HAproxy configs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About this time I've started to use &lt;a href="http://atom.io"&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; text editor, which is written in JavaScript,
so I ended up developing a couple of plugins for it using CoffeScript and JavaScript. I had no illusions about
JS after using dynamically typed languages for a long time, but I was very surprised by the tooling around this language.
It appeared to be extremely good and far superior to the one Python has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So my fourth job gave me a lot of opportunities to develop things in languages of my choice, so I've got
a lot of experience developing tools from scratch. Also I've learned Go and tried JS.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fifth job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I'm dealing with some complex systems, mostly in Python, and quite happy with it. I am surrounded by very smart
people and have enough challenges for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting solid basic knowledges in the university, I was learning only by myself. And even in the university
I was studying a lot of other Faculties courses material on my own to do their homework for money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for me, the only reasonable way to learn by myself is to be surrounded by smart people and to have tasks that
are more difficult than what you can handle right now. I've always had some challenging tasks,
and when my job stopped being challenging, I've changed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while I've been learning new programming languages, as an SysAdmin/SRE I was able to switch them easily
without loosing value as a worker, so I was learning more general things and not some particular language quirks
and bizarre tricks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Programming"></category><category term="Experience"></category></entry><entry><title>Board games are awesome</title><link href="http://bulimov.ru/personal/boardgames-love/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-31T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2016-08-31T00:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Bulimov</name></author><id>tag:bulimov.ru,2016-08-31:/personal/boardgames-love/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I's been awhile since I wrote anything in my blog, mostly because
I was moving to Ireland and was busy at my new job at Big Company™.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So as I can't write about all the cool technical things we have there,
I'll try to make this blog less tech-savvy and more personal and fun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a normal IT person I spend whole working day staring at the computer's
screen. While …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I's been awhile since I wrote anything in my blog, mostly because
I was moving to Ireland and was busy at my new job at Big Company™.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So as I can't write about all the cool technical things we have there,
I'll try to make this blog less tech-savvy and more personal and fun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a normal IT person I spend whole working day staring at the computer's
screen. While I love my job and all the high-tech stuff, I feel a great demand of
something more physical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as a good workout is what my body needs at the end of the day, a good
board game is what my mind needs after work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why do I love playing board games?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because moving all this lovely meeples, touching wooden components, holding
cards is so satisfying, and so opposite to using computer. It's so REAL, so
MATERIAL. And at the same time playing board games is fun and challenging,
and makes you use your brain in some different way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just look at this cute little animeeples from &lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/119890/agricola-all-creatures-big-and-small"&gt;Agricola: All Creatures Big And Small&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="animeeples" src="/images/animeeples.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't you want to touch them? Looking at them, it's hard to imagine how
intense and challenging is this game's mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course playing board games involves contacting with people, which is a
good thing for me.
While most of the time I play board games with my wife, I really enjoy regular
Board Game Nights at the office with my colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to recall when I started playing board games, but I've been playing
them at least 5 or 6 years, and now have a decent collection
and a clear understanding of what type of games I love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Just a quick overview of games I enjoy most.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, my top-3 list is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/119890/agricola-all-creatures-big-and-small"&gt;Agricola: All Creatures Big And Small&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/822/carcassonne"&gt;Carcassonne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/63628/manhattan-project"&gt;The Manhattan Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this games I own and play regularly with my wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a big company I prefer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/14996/ticket-ride-europe"&gt;Ticket To Ride: Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/146548/imadzhinarium"&gt;Имаджинариум&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ekivoki.ru"&gt;Экивоки&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, some of them are local Russian games, so I need to find some
equivalents here. Luckily, at Board Game Night I can try many new games for a company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I want to mention some old-school card games I love:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cribbage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rummy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what's great - there A LOT of board games to choose from, and every year new
games keep arriving. Almost anyone can find a setting he likes with game mechanics
he enjoys. It's so cool compared to my childhood, when most of the board games you
can find you must have to cut from some soviet magazines for kids, and it would
have been some simple 'roll dice, move forward' kind of game. You can take a look
at some of them in &lt;a href="http://www.gamer.ru/boardgames/o-nih-mechtali-vse-deti-sovetskie-nastolnye-igry-70h-90h-godov-foto-obzor"&gt;this nice overview (in Russian)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you haven't played board games - give it a try, it's so much fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Board Games"></category></entry></feed>