<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tmux on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</title>
    <link>//bulimov.me/tags/tmux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tmux on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//bulimov.me/tags/tmux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Switching from Tmux to Zellij</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2025/03/22/tmux-zellij/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2025/03/22/tmux-zellij/</guid>
      <description>When I wrote about refreshing my CLI setup, I mentioned how I gave Zellij a try, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find compelling reasons to replace tmux with it.&#xA;I also said that I will continue to experiment with it to see if I change my mind.&#xA;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that I found a couple of very good, if not immediately obvious, reasons that compelled me to switch to Zellij as my daily driver.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refreshing my CLI tools setup</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2024/09/22/refreshing-cli-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2024/09/22/refreshing-cli-setup/</guid>
      <description>Recently I decided to get out of my shell (pun intended) and check out the latest and greatest in shells, terminal multiplexers and terminal-based text editors.&#xA;After all, It&amp;rsquo;s been 8 years since I took a fresh look at how I use those invaluable CLI tools.&#xA;I still remember how on one of my first jobs I got so engrossed in the work that for a first month or so I completely neglected setting up my work machine, and worked in a stock Debian shell and terminal, which sure looked like a dog&amp;rsquo;s dinner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Открыл для себя плагины к tmux</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/it/%D0%9E%D1%82%D0%BA%D1%80%D1%8B%D0%BB-%D0%B4%D0%BB%D1%8F-%D1%81%D0%B5%D0%B1%D1%8F-%D0%BF%D0%BB%D0%B0%D0%B3%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%8B-%D0%BA-tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/it/%D0%9E%D1%82%D0%BA%D1%80%D1%8B%D0%BB-%D0%B4%D0%BB%D1%8F-%D1%81%D0%B5%D0%B1%D1%8F-%D0%BF%D0%BB%D0%B0%D0%B3%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%8B-%D0%BA-tmux/</guid>
      <description>Случилось чудесное - LOR принес мне пользу. Оттуда я узнал о плагине tmux-resurrect, а точнее, вообще о существовании плагинов для чудесного мультиплексора терминалов tmux.&#xA;С помощью имеющихся плагинов можно привести конфигурацию в более понятный вид, а также заменить свои костыли на костыли, поддерживаемые сообществом.&#xA;Я, к примеру:&#xA;сильно сократил конфигурацию, используя tmux-sensible; с помощью tmux-yank выкинул свои костыли для копирования в буфер обмена; смог убрать настройки для vi-образной навигации между панелями благодаря tmux-pain-control; обрел поиск с помощью tmux-copycat; теперь могу открывать выделенные файлы либо URL с помощью tmux-open; наконец, могу сохранять все открытые окна и панели tmux с использованием tmux-resurrect; </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
