<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vacuum Cleaner on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</title>
    <link>//bulimov.me/tags/vacuum-cleaner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vacuum Cleaner on Alexander Bulimov: Production Engineer and Scale Modeller</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//bulimov.me/tags/vacuum-cleaner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Repairing a robot vacuum cleaner</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2025/10/04/repairing-robot-vacuum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2025/10/04/repairing-robot-vacuum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to report that modern robot vacuum cleaners are fairly easy to repair, at least from the mechanical standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I guess the relatively large form factor allows for components to be big enough, and that there is no clear need to miniaturize everything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Debugging the robot vacuums from a software standpoint is a completely different affair, and not in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my particular case, my trusty &lt;a href=&#34;//bulimov.me/post/2023/08/13/robot-vacuum-amazing&#34;&gt;ECOVACS T8&lt;/a&gt; developed a problem with one of the driving wheels,&#xA;probably after being stuck on a cable or a sock way too often.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robot Vacuum Cleaner is an amazing invention</title>
      <link>//bulimov.me/post/2023/08/13/robot-vacuum-amazing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//bulimov.me/post/2023/08/13/robot-vacuum-amazing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using a robot vacuum cleaner for exactly one year now, so decided to summarize my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally I’m not a fan of all this &amp;lsquo;smart home&amp;rsquo; stuff, definitely very far from being a fanboy by all standards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But at the same time I’m a huge fan of automating everything, and thus was always interested in trying a robot vacuum cleaner. If anything, washing machine and a dishwasher already immensely help with other house chores, why not automate cleaning too?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
